Jaime Ferrando Huertas

■ fhjaime96@gmail.com | 😭 www.imjai.me | 🖸 github.com/jiwidi

Senior Machine Learning Engineer with a focus on information systems, I have a strong background in developing and implementing large-scale search and recommendation systems. My expertise lies in statistical analysis, machine learning algorithms, and artificial intelligence. I have a proven track record of successfully deploying and scaling machine learning solutions in real-world applications and serving millions of users.

Work Experience _____

EcomID Stockholm based

Co-Founder - Head of AI

· Lead AI Team

Shaped.ai Remote, Stockholm based

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

- · Develop and implement machine learning models and infrastructure to enable customers to build highly effective, real-time recommendation
- Build and deploy semantic search systems from recommendation models representations.
- Design and implement real-time feature-store and data ingestion pipelines to minimize train-inference disparities and merge pipelines for both batch and streaming.

Stockholm, Sweden

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

Feb 2020 - April 2022

November 2023 - Now

April 2022 - November 2023

- Organized H&M's inaugural Kaggle competition, involving over 2900 international teams and a prize fund of \$50,000.
- Engineered neural-based recommendation systems, significantly boosting customer engagement, revenue, and online interaction.
- Design and implementation of infrastructure on GCP for real-time recommendation model serving. Reduced ingestion time of user events to be ready for model inference from 16hours to 3seconds.
- Steered A/B tests, experimentation and established feedback mechanisms for internal dashboards.

Sandvik Stockholm, Sweden

Data Scientist Oct 2018 - Feb 2020

- Abnormal behavior modelling for multivariate distributions of high performing industrial processes.
- · Deployment and maintenance of inference servers within GCP.

Stockholm, Sweden

Polystar group

Abnormal behaviors within telecommunications networks.

Ahora freeware

Software Engineer Intern Jun 2016 - Oct 2017

· I designed a cloud-based library that seamlessly integrates with existing CRM for effortless file storage across cloud storage provides: Dropbox, Office365, and Google Drive.

Education

Data Scientist

Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence, Pattern Recognition and Digital Imaging

Valencia, Spain

Oct 2017 - July 2018

Valencia, Spain

UPV, Politecnic University of Valencia

- Cum laude master thesis
- Courses: Data Science, Programming for Data Science, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning, Statistical Theory and Methods, Learning Skills through Case Studies, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Statistical Learning

Bachelor in Computer Science

Valencia, Spain

UPV, Politecnic University of Valencia

- · Class representative.
- Part of the High performance class where only 30 students out of 450 would follow bachelors with english coursework.
- Exchange program with KTH Royal Institute of Technology.

Publications

MARCH 14, 2024

Skills

Programming Python, Java, C, C++, Javascript

ML Tools Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn, LightGBM, XGBoost, FAISS, Annoy, TensorFlow, Keras

Matplotlib, Seaborn, Statsmodels, NLTK, SpaCy, Gensim, ElasticSearch

Cloud tools AWS, Sagemaker, S3, Lambda, Jenkins, CircleCI, Azure, Jenkins, CircleCI

Google Cloud (GCP), Firebase, Bigquery, VertexAI, Dataflow, Pub/Sub

Databases/Data Platforms PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Cassandra, Hadoop, Spark, Hive, Databricks, ElasticSearch

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Docker, ŁTFX, Markdown), Microsoft Office, Git, Vim

Achievements

2022 **Organizer**, H&M Personalized Fashion Recommendations

Kaggle

2018 **2nd**, UniversityHack 2018 - National Cross university competition for data science modeling

Spain

Open Source work

Sklearn

Several improvements to the Partial Least Squares (PLS) implementation and helper methods.

Pytorch Audio

Added new baseline datasets (Tedlium 1, Tedlium 2, Tedlium 3) and code to facilitate reproducible experiments over one of the most famous ASR benchmarks.

C LAS-Pytorch

Open source Implementation of Listen, Attend and spell model for E2E ASR.

Behavior-Sequence-Transformer-Pytorch

Open source Implementation of Behavior-Sequence-Transformer, a published paper by Alibaba research that joins session and context based recommendation systems.

H&M Recommendation dataset

Released an open source recommendation dataset along with the hosted Kaggle competition.

Neural recommender systems at H&M

Master Thesis (Cum-laude graded) for Neural based recommender at H&M. Proposed models replaced existing ones in production.

Time series with Python

A use-case focused tutorial for time series forecasting with Python.

□ Jupyter-lab-docker-rpi

A Docker image to run JupyterLab on your Raspberry Pi.

Netflix-RNN-Recommender

Implicit recommender for Netflix dataset.

GMM-Classifier

Python implementation for a Gaussian mixture model classifier.

PLS Regression Tensorflow

PLS regression in TensorFlow 2.0.

OpenAI Game Challenges

My first ever project with AI where I solved the OpenAI game challenges with reinforcement learning.